<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Ulrich Schroeders — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:12:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ulrich-schroeders.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/publications/</guid>
      <description>Preprints  Schroeders, U., Mariss, A., Sauter, J., &amp;amp; Jankowsky, K. (2023, November 17). Predicting juvenile delinquency and criminal behavior in adulthood using machine learning. PsyArXiv preprint  Müller, S., Schroeders, U., Bachrach, N., Benecke, C., Cuevas, L., Doering, S., Elklit, A., Gutiérrez, F., Hengartner, M. P., Hogue, T. E., Hopwood, C. J., Mihura, J. L., Oltmanns, T. F., Paap, M. C. S., Pedersen, G., Renn, D., Ringwald, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Method-Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/method-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 17:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/method-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>Ant Colony Optimization script Ant Colony Optimization (ACO) mimics the foraging behavior of ants and is a popular optimization algorithm in computational sciences. Ants use pheromone tracks to find the shortest route from the nest to the food source, which generally accumulate faster on shorter routes which in turn attract more ants. Routes are constantly optimized until an efficient route is found. Due to its great flexibility the same principles can also be applied to psychological settings, for example, in the construction of short scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 09:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/research/</guid>
      <description>Technology-Based Assessment In the last decades, the digitalization of educational content, the integration of computers in different educational settings and the opportunity to connect knowledge and people via the Internet has led to fundamental changes in the way we gather, process, and evaluate information. Also, more and more tablet PCs or notebooks are used in schools and—in comparison to traditional sources of information such as text books—the Internet seems to be more appealing, versatile, and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bee Swarm Optimization (BSO)</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2022/12/BSO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2022/12/BSO/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Bees are amazing, little creatures&amp;rdquo; (Richardson, 2017) &amp;ndash; I agree. Bees have fascinated people since time immemorial, and yet even today there are still novel and fascinating discoveries (see the PLOS collection for some mind-boggling facts). Although bees as an insect species might seem as the prime example of state-building insects, highly social forms of community are the exception among bees. The large majority of all bee species are solitary bees or cuckoo bees that do not form insect states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum vitae</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/cv/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Dr. Ulrich Schroeders Professor of Psychological Assessment
Institute of Psychology, University of Kassel
Holländische Str. 36-38, Raum 3304, 34127 Kassel
tel +49 (0) 561 804-7529
Links  University of Kassel: https://www.uni-kassel.de/go/schroeders/ ResearchGate: https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Ulrich_Schroeders Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.de/citations?user=xnKlUWIAAAAJ Open Science Foundation: https://osf.io/eytc3/ Orcid-ID: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5225-1122 Web of Science: https://www.webofscience.com/wos/author/record/2124716  Education  10/2017 Full Professor of Psychological Assessment, University of Kassel 04/2017 Positive intermediate evaluation of Junior professorship 04/2014 Junior Professor of Educational Research, Member of the Bamberg Graduate School of Social Sciences (BAGSS), University of Bamberg 07/2010 PhD, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, Title of Thesis: &amp;ldquo;Measurement of Cognitive Abilities Using Modern Technologies: Artifacts, Equivalence, and New Constructs&amp;rdquo;, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin 05/2004 Diploma in Psychology, Julius-Maximilians-University Würzburg, Title of Thesis: &amp;ldquo;TeDDy &amp;ndash; Test zur Diagnose von Dyskalkulie in der 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests-Questionnaires</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/tests-questionnaires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 17:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/tests-questionnaires/</guid>
      <description>A 120 item gc test This is a 120 item measure of crystallized intelligence (gc), more precisely, declarative knowledge. Based on previous findings concerning the dimensionality of gc (Steger et al., 2019), we sampled items from four broad knowledge areas - humanities, life sciences, natural sciences, and social sciences. Each knowledge area contained three domains with ten items each, resulting in a total of 120 items. Items were selected to have a wide range of difficulty and to broadly and deeply cover the content domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the citations align with my research interests?</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2022/03/citation-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2022/03/citation-analysis/</guid>
      <description>When citations are traded as the currency of science, it is difficult to estimate the price of a publication in advance or to understand it afterwards. One has the impression that precisely the topics that are frequently cited are those not in focus of one&amp;rsquo;s interest. In contrast, the work that one finds most interesting, might receive little attention. But maybe this perception is biased. To get a better understanding which articles are cited, I would like to give a short bibliometric evaluation of my google scholar citations in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practice self commitment</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/best-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 12:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/best-practice/</guid>
      <description>Many standards in psychological research concerning the study design, data analysis, reporting and publishing have changed in the light of the so-called replication crisis. The following overview attempts to take this development into account to foster transparency, robustness, and integrity of our own research. My research team and I took the form of a voluntary commitment. The aim is to commit ourselves publicly and then work accordingly for all upcoming projects, starting Oct-21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment - Much ado about machine learning</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/07/gc-age-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/07/gc-age-ml/</guid>
      <description>This is the third post in a series on a paper — &amp;quot;Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment&amp;quot; — we recently published in Intelligence. The first post reflected on how knowledge is organized, the second post dealt with psychometric issues. This post is going to be more mathematical (yes, there will be some formulae) and it will be a cautionary note on the use of machine learning algorithms. Machine learning algorithms have positively influenced research in various scientific disciplines such as astrophysics, genetics, or medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment - A modeling perspective</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/05/gc-age-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 05:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/05/gc-age-modeling/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in a series on a recent paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment&amp;rdquo; that we wrote with Luc Watrin and Oliver Wilhelm. The first post dealt with the way how we conceptualize the organization of knowledge in a hierarchy in a multidimensional knowledge space. The second post reflects on the way we measure or model knowledge. In textbooks knowledge assessments have a special standing, because they can be modeled both from a reflective and a formative perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment - A hierarchy of knowledge</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/05/gc-age-hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2021/05/gc-age-hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>We published a new paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Age-related nuances in knowledge assessment&amp;rdquo; in Intelligence. I really like this paper because it deals with on the way we assess, model, and understand knowledge. And, btw, it employs machine learning methods. Thus, both in terms of content and methodology it hopefully sets a stage for future research avenues that are promising to follow up on. I would like to cover some of the key findings in a series of blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer Responsible for journalistic editorial content according to § 55 II RstV:
Prof. Dr. Ulrich Schroeders
Professor of Psychological Assessment
Institute of Psychology, University of Kassel
Holländische Str. 36-38, Raum 3304, 34127 Kassel
tel +49 (0) 561 804-7529</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science self-concept – More than the sum of its parts?</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2020/03/science-self-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2020/03/science-self-concepts/</guid>
      <description>The article &amp;ldquo;Science Self-Concept – More Than the Sum of its Parts?&amp;rdquo; has now been published in &amp;ldquo;The Journal of Experimental Education&amp;rdquo; (btw in existence since 1932). The first 50 copies are free, in case you are interested.
My first preprint. 😀Is a general science self-concept equivalent to an aggregated subject-specific science concept? It&amp;#39;s about different modeling approaches, measurement invariance and concepts of equivalence. Check it out! Comment if you like: https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for equivalence of test data across media</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2019/04/equivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2019/04/equivalence/</guid>
      <description>In 2009, I wrote a small chapter that was part of an EU conference book on the transition to computer-based assessment. Now and then I&amp;rsquo;m coming back to this piece of work - in my teaching and my publications (e.g., the EJPA paper on testing reasoning ability across different devices). Now I want to make it publically available. Hopefully, it will be interesting to some of you. The chapter is the (unaltered) preprint version of the book chapter, so if you want to cite it, please use the following citation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls in measurement invariance testing</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2019/01/df-mgcfa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 09:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2019/01/df-mgcfa/</guid>
      <description>In a new paper in the European Journal of Psychological Assessment, Timo Gnambs and I examined the soundness of reporting measurement invariance (MI) testing in the context of multigroup confirmatory factor analysis (MGCFA). Of course, there are several good primers on MI testing (e.g., Cheung &amp;amp; Rensvold, 2002; Wicherts &amp;amp; Dolan, 2010) and textbooks that elaborate on the theoretical base (e.g., Millsap, 2011), but a clearly written tutorial with example syntax how to implement MI practically was still missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New methods and assessment approaches in intelligence research</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/11/si-joi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 09:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/11/si-joi/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you have seen my recent Tweet: Please share this call and contribute to a new Special Issue on &amp;quot;New Methods and Assessment Approaches in Intelligence Research&amp;quot; in the @Jintelligence1, we are guest-editing together with Hülür, @HildePsych, and @pdoebler. More information: https://t.co/PevdPeyRgm pic.twitter.com/Y6hRllQa8m
&amp;mdash; Ulrich Schroeders (@Navajoc0d3) November 11, 2018  And this is the complete Call for the Special Issue in the Journal of Intelligence
 Dear Colleagues,
Our understanding of intelligence has been&amp;mdash;and still is&amp;mdash;significantly influenced by the development and application of new computational and statistical methods, as well as novel testing procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-analysis proctored vs. unproctored assessment</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/10/ma-proctored-vs-unproctored/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/10/ma-proctored-vs-unproctored/</guid>
      <description>Our meta-analysis – Steger, Schroeders, &amp;amp; Gnambs (2018) – comparing test-scores of proctored vs. unproctored assessment is now available as online first publication and sometime in the future to be published in the European Journal of Psychological Assessment. In more detail, we examined mean score differences and correlations between both assessment contexts with a three-level random-effects meta-analysis based on 49 studies with 109 effect sizes. We think this is a timely topic since web-based assessments are frequently compromised by a lack of control over the participants&#39; test-taking behavior, but researchers are nevertheless in the need to compare the data obtained through unproctored test conditions with data from controlled settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal measurement invariance testing with categorical data</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/09/long-MI-categorical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/09/long-MI-categorical/</guid>
      <description>In a recent paper – Edossa, Schroeders, Weinert, &amp;amp; Artelt, 2018 – we came across the issue of longitudinal measurement invariance testing with categorical data. There are quite good primers and textbooks on longitudinal measurement invariance testing with continuous data (e.g., Geiser, 2013). However, at the time of writing the manuscript there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an application of measurement invariance testing in the longitudinal run with categorical data. In case your are interest in using such an invariance testing procedure, we uploaded the R syntax for all measurement invariance steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recalculating df in MGCFA testing</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/df-mgcfa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/df-mgcfa/</guid>
      <description>function recalculate_df() {var nind = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num1&#39;).value);var nlat = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num2&#39;).value);var ncross = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num3&#39;).value);var northo = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num4&#39;).value);var nres = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num5&#39;).value);var ngroup = parseInt(document.getElementById(&#39;num6&#39;).value);var answer1 = document.getElementById(&#39;df_conf&#39;);var answer2 = document.getElementById(&#39;df_metr&#39;);var answer3 = document.getElementById(&#39;df_scal&#39;);var answer4 = document.getElementById(&#39;df_resi&#39;);var answer5 = document.getElementById(&#39;df_stri&#39;);var answer6 = document.getElementById(&#39;delta_1&#39;);var answer7 = document.getElementById(&#39;delta_2&#39;);var answer8 = document.getElementById(&#39;delta_3&#39;);var answer9 = document.getElementById(&#39;delta_4&#39;);obs = ((nind*(nind+1)/2) + nind) * ngroup ;est = ((2*nind + (nind + ncross) + ((nlat-northo)*((nlat-northo)-1)/2)) + nres) * ngroup ;answer1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale - A drosophila melanogaster of psychological assessment</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/rses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/rses/</guid>
      <description>I had the great chance to co-author two recent publications of Timo Gnambs, both dealing with the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale (RSES; Rosenberg, 1965). As a reminder, the RSES is a popular ten item self-report instrument measuring a respondent&amp;rsquo;s global self-worth and self-respect. But basically both papers are not about the RSES per se, rather they are applications of two recently introduced powerful and flexible extensions of the Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) Framework: Meta-Analytic Structural Equation Modeling (MASEM) and Local Weighted Structural Equation Modeling (LSEM), which will be described in more detail later on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less is more - A WordPress blog goes Hugo</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 10:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/hugo/</guid>
      <description>After several years running this website on WordPress, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a change. WordPress has become overloaded, sometimes the back-end is not responsive, and writing a blog post is too tedious&amp;mdash;in a nutshell, WordPress isn&amp;rsquo;t right for me. Hugo is an open-source static site generator built around Google&amp;rsquo;s Go programming language, which is renowned for its speed. In contrast to dynamic websites that heavily rely on php-scripting and MySQL-databases that are used to store all the content, static websites consist of html, css, and js.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equivalence of screen versus print reading comprehension depends on task complexity and proficiency</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/08/pc-vs-pp-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 07:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/08/pc-vs-pp-reading/</guid>
      <description>Reference. Lenhard, W., Schroeders, U., &amp;amp; Lenhard, A. (2017). Equivalence of screen versus print reading comprehension depends on task complexity and proficiency. Discourse Processes, 54(5-6), 427–445. doi: https://doi.org/10.1080/0163853X.2017.1319653
Abstract. As reading and reading assessment become increasingly implemented on electronic devices, the question arises whether reading on screen is comparable with reading on paper. To examine potential differences, we studied reading processes on different proficiency and complexity levels. Specifically, we used data from the standardization sample of the German reading comprehension test ELFE II (n = 2,807), which assesses reading at word, sentence, and text level with separate speeded subtests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitment to research transparency and open science</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/01/open-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 23:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/01/open-science/</guid>
      <description>I signed the Commitment to Research Transparency and Open Science, which was initially worded by Felix Schönbrodt, Markus Maier, Moritz Heene, and Michael Zehetleitner from the LMU Munich. The first paragraph of this commitment summarizes the overall aim:
 We embrace the values of openness and transparency in science. We believe that such research practices increase the informational value and impact of our research, as the data can be reanalyzed and synthesized in future studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-heuristics in short scale construction</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/01/metaheuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2017/01/metaheuristics/</guid>
      <description>Reference. Schroeders, U., Wilhelm, O., &amp;amp; Olaru, G. (2016). Meta-heuristics in short scale construction: Ant Colony Optimization and Genetic Algorithm. PLOS ONE, 11, e0167110. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0167110
Abstract. The advent of large-scale assessment, but also the more frequent use of longitudinal and multivariate approaches to measurement in psychological, educational, and sociological research, caused an increased demand for psychometrically sound short scales. Shortening scales economizes on valuable administration time, but might result in inadequate measures because reducing an item set could: a) change the internal structure of the measure, b) result in poorer reliability and measurement precision, c) deliver measures that cannot effectively discriminate between persons on the intended ability spectrum, and d) reduce test-criterion relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/archives/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/archives/archives/</guid>
      <description>This page contains an archive of all posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
