<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LSEM on US</title>
    <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/tags/lsem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LSEM on US</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Ulrich Schroeders — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 09:04:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ulrich-schroeders.de/tags/lsem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 09:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/fixed/research/</guid>
      <description>Technology-Based Assessment In the last decades, the digitalization of educational content, the integration of computers in different educational settings and the opportunity to connect knowledge and people via the Internet has led to fundamental changes in the way we gather, process, and evaluate information. Also, more and more tablet PCs or notebooks are used in schools and—in comparison to traditional sources of information such as text books—the Internet seems to be more appealing, versatile, and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science self-concept – More than the sum of its parts?</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2020/03/science-self-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2020/03/science-self-concepts/</guid>
      <description>The article &amp;ldquo;Science Self-Concept – More Than the Sum of its Parts?&amp;rdquo; has now been published in &amp;ldquo;The Journal of Experimental Education&amp;rdquo; (btw in existence since 1932). The first 50 copies are free, in case you are interested.
My first preprint. 😀Is a general science self-concept equivalent to an aggregated subject-specific science concept? It&amp;#39;s about different modeling approaches, measurement invariance and concepts of equivalence. Check it out! Comment if you like: https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale - A drosophila melanogaster of psychological assessment</title>
      <link>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/rses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ulrich-schroeders.de/2018/01/rses/</guid>
      <description>I had the great chance to co-author two recent publications of Timo Gnambs, both dealing with the Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale (RSES; Rosenberg, 1965). As a reminder, the RSES is a popular ten item self-report instrument measuring a respondent&amp;rsquo;s global self-worth and self-respect. But basically both papers are not about the RSES per se, rather they are applications of two recently introduced powerful and flexible extensions of the Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) Framework: Meta-Analytic Structural Equation Modeling (MASEM) and Local Weighted Structural Equation Modeling (LSEM), which will be described in more detail later on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
